{"tossups": [{"question": "This state\u2019s Ybor City was a center for cigar manufacturing, and its Hialeah is home to many marielitos and balseros who arrived before the wet foot-dry foot policy was implemented. Elian Gonzalez was deported from this state as a child, an event which is thought to have led many in its large Cuban-American community to turn against Al Gore in the close presidential election in this state in 2000. For ten points, name this US state, some 90 miles north of Cuba.", "answer": "<b> Florida</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This figure\u2019s previous lives and actions are outlined in the Jataka tales. This figure\u2019s mother had a dream of a white elephant piercing her side before this figure\u2019s birth. This religious figure\u2019s birthplace is located in modern day Lumbini, Nepal. This figure achieved enlightenment while sitting under the Bodhi Tree. For ten points, name this religious figure from Ancient India, who founded a namesake meditative religion and was originally named Siddartha Gautama.", "answer": "The<b> Buddha</b> (accept<b> Siddartha</b> or<b> Gautama</b> before it is mentioned)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "This colony gained independence after talks with Patrice Lumumba and Moise Tshombe led to Joseph Kasavubu becoming its first president. A hundred years earlier, this colony was explored and subsequently claimed by Henry Morgan Stanley. The Casement Report detailed atrocities carried out in this colony by the<em> Force Publique</em>, which utilized forced labor in harvesting rubber. For ten points, name this colony once privately controlled by King Leopold II of Belgium.", "answer": "Belgian<b> Congo</b> (accept<b> Congo</b> Free State or Democratic Republic of the<b> Congo</b>, prompt on DRC)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In one battle, this city was defended by a floating chain placed on logs to impede ship movement. An emperor legendarily turned into marble after the fall of this city, which was assaulted by the massive Dardanelles gun built by Orban. This city was protected by the walls of the Golden Horn and defenders utilizing Greek Fire. This city lost control of the Bosphorus prior to its fall to Mehmed II in 1453. For ten points, what capital of the Byzantines fell to the Ottoman Empire?", "answer": "<b> Constantinople</b> (accept<b> Istanbul</b> or<b> Byzantium</b>) Page 1", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "After 1885, this natural formation was named for a New York lawyer and prospector, but its original Lakota Sioux name means \u201cSix Grandfathers.\u201d Historian Doane Robinson\u2019s original plan for this formation included Red Cloud, Meriwether Lewis, William Clark, and \u201cBuffalo Bill\u201d Cody. Its sculptor, Gutzon Borglum, thought this formation needed to appeal to a broader audience and chose four other subjects. For ten points, what is this National Memorial in the Black Hills of South Dakota, featuring the faces of four U.S. presidents?", "answer": "Mount<b> Rushmore</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Viscount Rothermere founded a business of this type that advertised as being \u201cfor office boys.\u201dOne of these companies claimed that a missile it photographed was poised to hit \u201cGaltieri\u2019s gauchos.\u201dDuring the Winter of Discontent that business of this type popularized the phrase \u201cCrisis? What Crisis?\u201dand is one of several of them owned by Rupert Murdoch. For ten points, name these businesses that include<em> The Sun</em> and the<em> London Times</em>.", "answer": "<b> Newspaper</b>s", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "In Isabel Allende\u2019s novel<em> Daughter of Fortune</em>, one of these events causes Joaquin to leave a pregnant Eliza. A Skookum king offers over $1000 gained from one of these events to buy a character that is mistreated by Hal, Charles, and Mercedes before befriending John Thornton. That character, Buck, appears in the Jack London novel<em> The Call of the Wild</em>, which is set against the backdrop of one of these events in the Yukon. For ten points, name these events, a famous example of which saw miners flock to California in 1849.", "answer": "<b> Gold rush</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "Kate Smith debuted a modified version of this song during the 1938 Armistice Day broadcast of her radio show. To avoid political undertones, this song\u2019s lyrics \u201cto the right\u201d were changed to \u201cthrough the night.\u201d Woody Guthrie wrote \u201cThis Land Is Your Land\u201d in direct response to this song that describes a light shining \u201cfrom the mountains, to the prairies.\u201d This song urges the listener to \u201cstand beside\u201d and\u201cguide\u201d the central land. Ending by calling the title country \u201cMy home sweet home,\u201d For ten points, name this patriotic song by Irving Berlin.", "answer": "<b> \u201cGod Bless America\u201d</b> Page 2", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Following this event, a New York merchant named Robert Murray offered compensation to its victims but was refused. This event legendarily began with the codewords \u201cthis meeting can do nothing more to save our country\u201d after Thomas Hutchinson refused to allow the<em> Dartmouth</em> to leave. This event helped contribute to the Intolerable Acts and the closing of a certain harbor. For ten points, name this event in which colonists dressed up as Mohawks and destroyed crates of Darjeeling.", "answer": "<b> Boston Tea Party</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A king of this name became the final monarch to dismiss an English prime minister when he removed Lord Melbourne. Child labour was banned during the reign of a king of this name, the last of the Hanoverian dynasty. A king of this name took power when his predecessor\u2019s Declaration of Indulgence led to that man\u2019s overthrow. Rotten boroughs were eliminated in an attempt to expand votership when the\u201cGreat Reform Bill\u201d was passed under a king of this name. For ten points, the Catholic James II was overthrown by a king of what name during the Glorious Revolution?", "answer": "<b> William</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This son of the Younger Lady may have died as a result of birth defects, though other theories include sickle cell anemia and a blow to the head. This man reversed the religious policies of his father Akhenaten and rejected Aten in favor of Amun-Re. In 1922, this man\u2019s tomb was discovered by Harold Carter in the Valley of the Kings. For ten points, name this boy pharaoh whose tomb is the subject of a namesake curse.", "answer": "<b> Tut</b>ankhamun (accept King<b> Tut</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Martin Fernandez De Encisco is credited with being the first European to write about this particular food, an undomesticated variety of which is known as its<em> criollo</em> variant. The most popular variety in the world is named after the man who developed the variety in California, Rudolf Hass. The U.S. lifted a ban on imports of this fruit during the 1990s, and the consumption of this single-seeded berry has tripled on Super Bowl Sundays due to its use in a popular dip. For ten points, name this green fruit used to make guacamole.", "answer": "<b> Avocado</b> pear (accept<b> Alligator pear</b> or<b> Persea americana</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this U.S. paper currency which includes a portrait of the eighteenth president, Ulysses Grant.", "answer": "United States<b> fifty-dollar bill </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In 1985, this company purchased Hughes Aircraft and merged it with Delco Electronics.</b> <b>Alfred</b> <b>Sloan</b> <b>began</b> <b>the</b> <b>practice</b> <b>of</b> <b>positioning</b> <b>brands</b> <b>of</b> <b>this</b> <b>company</b> <b>to</b> <b>specific</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>socioeconomic demographics. A 1937 sit-down strike launched by the (+)</b> <b>UAW was</b> <b>UAW was</b> <b>ended when this company came to an agreement with its workers. William Durant founded this company, who launched a failed campaign to buy out (*)</b> Ford. Founded in Flint, Michigan, for ten points, name this American car manufacturer whose brands include Buick and Chevrolet.", "answer": "<b> General Motors</b> (accept<b> GM</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>After a defeat in this war\u2019s Battle of Worcester, a man who was later restored as king of his country escaped pursuit by hiding in the Royal Oak. The cavalry of Prince Rupert</b> <b>proved decisive in the victory of one side in this war at the Battle of (+)</b> <b>Edgehill, but</b> <b>he was soundly defeated at the Battle of Marston Moor. With the victory of the New Model Army at the Battle of Naseby, the (*)</b> Roundheads defeated the Royalist Cavaliers to win the first phase of this war. For ten points, name this 17th-century war that ended in the victory of the Parliamentarian forces of Oliver Cromwell.", "answer": "<b> English Civil</b> War", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this capital of South Vietnam.", "answer": "<b> Saigon</b> (accept<b> Ho Chi Minh City</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>During the Second World War, this astronaut served as a gunner on the</b><em><b> Cogswell</b></em><b> during the Battle of Okinawa. As a 47-year old, this man became the oldest man to ever walk on</b> <b>the (+)</b> <b>moon as commander of Apollo 14, in which capacity he was the first man to hit a</b> <b>golf ball in space. This man nearly broke his hand in anger after Yuri Gagarin was sent to space a (*)</b> month before this man took off in<em> Freedom 7</em>, the first manned mission of Project Mercury. For ten points, name this first American in space.", "answer": "Alan<b> Shepard</b> Page 9", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}